mhmedical.com 2016-12-05

# Privacy

**Privacy Notice  **

**Data Collection and Use**

When you subscribe to the McGraw-Hill Medical’s online products (such as ClinicalAccess, AccessMedicine, AccessAnesthesiology, AccessEmergency Medicine, AccessPediatrics, AccessPharmacy, AccessPhysiotherapy, AccessSurgery, OMMBID, Harrison's Online, and the LANGE Educational Library) or register for a trial subscription, we collect certain personal information, such as your name, contact information, and e-mail address. We use this information to process your order and manage your subscription. This information is stored in a secure database in the U.S. and access is limited to authorized persons.   
Your e-mail address is added to our electronic mailing list so that, from time to time, we can send you information about new features, additions, and changes to our Web site. If you do not want to receive e-mail alerts, you may indicate this on your registration form; or you can change this at any time by going to the Edit My Profile section of your “My Access” account. 

McGraw-Hill Medical may also make subscriber information available to other units within McGraw-Hill Education, LLC as well as to selected outside companies whose products or services we feel may be of interest to you. You can opt out of this at any time by visiting our Opt Out form.

If you are an individual trial user or an individual subscriber, you may also review and request changes to your information online at any time by going to the Contact Us page.  
Cookies and Web Technology

The Access products by McGraw-Hill Medical make use of "session" cookies. These are small bits of data that we send to your computer in order to improve your user experience. For example, the cookie keeps track of the fact that you have signed in so that when you move from one page to another, you don't have to reenter your user name and password. Session cookies are removed as soon as you log out or close your browser.   
In order to change these cookie preferences, you must change your browser's preferences to disable or delete cookies. Please note that disabling cookies for some services may affect your ability to use that service. Security information is specific to each browser and operating system. Please check with your browser's specific company for more information, or visit the “Help” link directly in your browser.   
An IP address is a number that's automatically assigned to your computer when you connect to a network. Web servers—the computers that present Web pages—automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We identify IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to our institutional customers, and to audit the use of our site. As is typical, when visitors request pages from McGraw-Hill Medical, our servers log the visitors' IP addresses, referrer site and user-agent information. We do not normally link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which means that a user's session will be logged, but the user remains anonymous to us. We use such information to identify a user when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our house rules or terms of service or to protect our service, site, customers, or others. 

**McGraw-Hill Education Customer Privacy**  
Please be assured that we take your concerns about privacy seriously, and take every reasonable effort to protect it. To that end, McGraw-Hill Education, LLC has developed a comprehensive customer privacy policy. If you'd like more information about our use of customer data, please review McGraw-Hill Education, LLC Customer Privacy Policy. 

If you have questions or comments about our customer privacy policy or you would like to confirm the accuracy of the information collected from you, please mail your concerns to: Chief Privacy Officer, McGraw-Hill Education, LLC, 2 Penn Plaza, 20th Floor, New York, NY 10121-2298 or email [privacy@mheducation.com](mailto:privacy@mheducation.com?subject=Privacy%20Notice%20Concerns).
